<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Visible Data</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Visible Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny modules to reduce duplication in apps</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/07/09/2019-07-09-shiny-modules-to-reduce-duplication-in-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/07/09/2019-07-09-shiny-modules-to-reduce-duplication-in-apps/</guid>
      <description>Shiny apps are awesome, with a bit of training you can build fairly impressive interactive web apps. But at some point, the subject of “shiny modules” will rear its head.
When I started learning modules, I found most of the existing articles focus on the technical-side of things and don’t focus on the benefits of using modules - they can significantly simplify and improve your apps.
I’m going to put together a few different tutorials on real-world Shiny apps and how modules can be used to improve them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One weird regex matches 97% of DOI...</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/03/13/2019-03-13_extracting-doi-from-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/03/13/2019-03-13_extracting-doi-from-text/</guid>
      <description>At least once a month I’m tasked with something that involves working with DOI, but I’ve never bothered to write a function for extracting these from texts. Time to end that by putting together a tidyversesque add_doi() function!
… wait, why?
The R for Data Science book has lots of excellent advice, including this snippet about reducing duplicated code by writing functions:
So, what are DOI? DOI (Digital Object Identifiers) are the gold standard for citations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#rmdnews updates 2019-03-06</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/03/06/2019-03-06-rmdnews-updates-2019-03-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/03/06/2019-03-06-rmdnews-updates-2019-03-06/</guid>
      <description>It’s hard keeping up to date with the awesome new things that we can do with #rstats. There are new packages and interesting new use cases of existing 📦 coming out all of the time. Mara Averick (@dataandme) is an incredible source of overviews and introductions to awesome stuff, if you don’t already follow her then do so immediately.
But how about 📦 updates? We often upgrade a package in a rush when we’re told the 📦 we want to install requires a new version of X.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where is the centre of University of Oxford?</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/02/18/2019-02-18_oxford-centres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/02/18/2019-02-18_oxford-centres/</guid>
      <description>.panel-heading .accordion-toggle:after { /* symbol for &#34;opening&#34; panels */ font-family: &#39;Glyphicons Halflings&#39;; /* essential for enabling glyphicon */ content: &#34;\e114&#34;; /* adjust as needed, taken from bootstrap.css */ float: right; /* adjust as needed */ color: grey; /* adjust as needed */ } .panel-heading .accordion-toggle.collapsed:after { /* symbol for &#34;collapsed&#34; panels */ content: &#34;\e080&#34;; /* adjust as needed, taken from bootstrap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes in class</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/12/19/2019-xx-xx_draft_notes-in-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/12/19/2019-xx-xx_draft_notes-in-class/</guid>
      <description>Something I feel simulataneously confident &amp;amp; unconfident is whether I should give students handouts for my training courses before the event.
It’s difficult to get a good handle on what other folks do. I ran an extremely pitiful Twitter poll with 7 responses (43% give handsouts during the course, 29% give handouts before).
So I’ve decided to create a survey of both students and trainers that I will try to spread as wide and broadly as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ggmap after July 2018</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/12/05/2018-12-05-using-ggmap-after-july-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/12/05/2018-12-05-using-ggmap-after-july-2018/</guid>
      <description>ggmap is an awesome package for creating maps with ggplot2. If you’ve seen a nice looking map built with ggplot2 I can almost guarantee you that it uses ggmap to look that good. The ggmap package is used to obtain base maps from the APIs of a number of online mapping tools, the one we care about here is the base maps from Google Maps (because they’re very good).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crawling DOI from a SAGE</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/11/12/2018-11-12-crawling-doi-from-a-sage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/11/12/2018-11-12-crawling-doi-from-a-sage/</guid>
      <description>Citable Author Martin John Hadley (orcid.org/0000-0002-3039-6849)     Citable Data Scrapes a delicate URL scheme from SAGE Publishing     Citable Code .Rmd on GitHub    Recently a friend told me they were doing a systematic review of the Hand Therap Journal published by SAGE. They wanted a way to scrape the journal for all publications, without going mad in the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great circles with sf and leaflet</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/02/28/2018-02-28_great-circles-with-sf-and-leaflet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/02/28/2018-02-28_great-circles-with-sf-and-leaflet/</guid>
      <description>Citable Author Martin John Hadley (orcid.org/0000-0002-3039-6849)     Citable Data No real data used.     Citable Code .Rmd on GitHub    Surprisingly often I’m asked to help folks build maps which visualise the journeys between geographic locations, in the bad old days of early 2017 I would have used the geospheres package and sp.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>